Privacy Policy
==============

Your privacy is critically important to us. At Nabu Casa, Inc., we have a few fundamental principles:

* We don’t ask you for personal information unless we truly need it. (We can’t stand services that ask you for things like your gender or income level for no apparent reason.)
* We don’t share your personal information with anyone except to comply with the law, develop our products, or protect our rights.
* We don’t store personal information on our servers unless required for the ongoing operation of one of our services.

If you have questions about deleting or correcting your personal data please contact our support team.

Website Visitors
----------------

Like most website operators, Nabu Casa, Inc. collects non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. Nabu Casa, Inc.’s purpose in collecting non-personally identifying information is to better understand how Nabu Casa, Inc.’s visitors use its website. From time to time, Nabu Casa, Inc. may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website.

Nabu Casa, Inc. also collects potentially personally-identifying information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses for logged in users and for users leaving comments on the blog or forums. Nabu Casa, Inc. only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below.

Gathering of Personally-Identifying Information
-----------------------------------------------

Certain visitors to Nabu Casa, Inc.’s websites choose to interact with Nabu Casa, Inc. in ways that require Nabu Casa, Inc. to gather personally-identifying information. The amount and type of information that Nabu Casa, Inc. gathers depends on the nature of the interaction. For example, we ask visitors who create a forum account to provide a username and an email address. Those who engage in transactions with Nabu Casa, Inc. are asked to provide additional information, including as necessary the personal and financial information required to process those transactions. In each case, Nabu Casa, Inc. collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with Nabu Casa, Inc.. Nabu Casa, Inc. does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below. And visitors can always refuse to supply personally-identifying information, with the caveat that it may prevent them from engaging in certain website-related activities.

Aggregated Statistics
---------------------

Nabu Casa, Inc. may collect statistics about the behavior of visitors to its websites. For instance, Nabu Casa, Inc. may monitor the most popular component documentation. Nabu Casa, Inc. may display this information publicly or provide it to others. However, Nabu Casa, Inc. does not disclose personally-identifying information other than as described below.

Protection of Certain Personally-Identifying Information
--------------------------------------------------------

Nabu Casa, Inc. discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only to those of its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations that (i) need to know that information in order to process it on Nabu Casa, Inc.’s behalf or to provide services available at Nabu Casa, Inc.’s websites, and (ii) that have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees, contractors and affiliated organizations may be located outside of your home country; by using Nabu Casa, Inc.’s websites, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. Nabu Casa, Inc. will not rent or sell potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information to anyone. Other than to its employees, contractors and affiliated organizations, as described above, Nabu Casa, Inc. discloses potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information only in response to a subpoena, court order or other governmental request, or when Nabu Casa, Inc. believes in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect the property or rights of Nabu Casa, Inc., third parties or the public at large. If you are a registered user of an Nabu Casa, Inc. website and have supplied your email address, Nabu Casa, Inc. may occasionally send you an email to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what’s going on with Nabu Casa, Inc. and our products. We primarily use our various product blogs to communicate this type of information, so we expect to keep this type of email to a minimum. If you send us a request (for example via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. Nabu Casa, Inc. takes all measures reasonably necessary to protect against the unauthorized access, use, alteration or destruction of potentially personally-identifying and personally-identifying information.

Cookies
-------

A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. Nabu Casa, Inc. uses cookies to help Nabu Casa, Inc. identify and track visitors, their usage of Nabu Casa, Inc. website, and their website access preferences. Nabu Casa, Inc. visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using Nabu Casa, Inc.’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of Nabu Casa, Inc.’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

Business Transfers
------------------

If Nabu Casa, Inc., or substantially all of its assets, were acquired, or in the unlikely event that Nabu Casa, Inc. goes out of business or enters bankruptcy, user information would be one of the assets that is transferred or acquired by a third party. You acknowledge that such transfers may occur, and that any acquirer of Nabu Casa, Inc. may continue to use your personal information as set forth in this policy.

Privacy Policy Changes
----------------------

Although most changes are likely to be minor, Nabu Casa, Inc. may change its Privacy Policy from time to time, and in Nabu Casa, Inc.’s sole discretion. Nabu Casa, Inc. encourages visitors to frequently check this page for any changes to its Privacy Policy. Your continued use of this site after any change in this Privacy Policy will constitute your acceptance of such change.

### Change log

* September 16, 2018: Initial version
* May 28, 2020: Removed reference to WordPress and social media logins as they are not used

_This privacy policy has been adapted from the [Home Assistant privacy policy](https://home-assistant.io/privacy/) and is licensed [Creative Commons ShareAlike](https://creativecommons.org/licenses/by-sa/4.0/)._

© Nabu Casa, Inc. - 15 Hubble Suite 200, Irvine, CA 92618

[Support](https://www.nabucasa.com/support) - [Contact Us](mailto:hello@nabucasa.com) - [Privacy Policy](https://www.nabucasa.com/privacy_policy) - [Terms of Service](https://www.nabucasa.com/tos)
